<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Geocaching | Good good study, day day up]]></title>
  <link href="http://aleung.github.io/blog/tags/geocaching/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aleung.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-07T00:01:53+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://aleung.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Leo Liang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazing, I got the geocoin which was sent to me from Italy two years ago!]]></title>
    <link href="http://aleung.github.io/blog/2010/06/28/Amazing-I-got-the-geocoin-which-was-sent-to-me-from-Italy-two-years-ago-/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-28T16:35:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://aleung.github.io/blog/2010/06/28/Amazing-I-got-the-geocoin-which-was-sent-to-me-from-Italy-two-years-ago-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/leoliang/4741853682/"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4121/4741853682_e9e93e2010.jpg" alt="Geocoin ALEUNG 1" /></a></p>

<p>This picture was taken at 18:44 18-Jun-2010, when I picked up the geocoin <a href="http://www.geocaching.com/track/details.aspx?id=1007428">ALEUNG 1</a> from the cache <a href="http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=f4f03572-94c5-440a-ae7e-ce1f755a069b">Golden Triangle</a>. The coin has traveled for two and a half years and over 21 thousand kilometers fromVeneto, Italy before it came to Guangzhou, China.</p>

<p>If you don’t know what is Geocaching, please refer to the definition on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geocaching">Wikipedia</a>. In simple saying, it’s a game that someone hide something (a cache) and publish the coordinate (latitude and longitude) on Internet and then other players seek it with help of a GPS receiver. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geocoin">Geocoin</a> is a special kind of coin each has an unique number that can be traced on geocaching website. Geocaching players pick up a coin from one cache and drop it into another cache, so that the coin can travel from cache to cache, even around the world.</p>

<p>The story began from Oct 2006, Italian geocacher <a href="http://www.geocaching.com/profile/?guid=b160e421-bca1-4b08-9c48-7944b4f019dc">i5fzi</a> came to Guangzhou for the Canton Fair. He contacted me on <a href="http://www.geocaching.com/">geocaching.com</a>.He didn’t know me before, but I was almost the only cacher in Guangzhou at that time. So it was geocaching that make us know each other. He kindly invited me for dinner and I suggested him some caches to find.</p>

<p>After i5fzi came back to Italy, he sent out several geocoins as present to me and Cherrie, who was his translator in Guangzhou. The goal of these coins are to reach my caches in Guangzhou. But unfortunately most of the geocoins were missed in there trip, this one I got is the only survival – I am so lucky to get it.</p>

<p>From this <a href="http://www.geocaching.com/track/map_gm.aspx?ID=1007428">map</a> you can see where the coin has been in. It visited some places in Europe then flied to HongKong, and then held by AirQ for a long time, until it was put in Guangzhou. I also thank AirQ, if AirQ didn’t hold and take it to Guangzhou, I guess this coin would have been lost as its friends. The last hotel the coin slept was KowloonW’s <a href="http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=f4f03572-94c5-440a-ae7e-ce1f755a069b">Golden Triangle</a>, but it isn’t shown on the map because not recorded on the website. KowloonW was very nice to keep the coin to avoid loss until I have time to fetch it.</p>

<p>Geocaching is so an amazing game. Thank you, all my friends in this game!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
